SOHAM NAIK KHAWTE

FULL STACK ENGINEER

London, UK | 07396737271 | soham.khawte2024@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sohamkh

SUMMARY

A dedicated computer science professional with a strong educational background with a blend of academic knowledge and industry experience, enthusiastic about delivering outstanding quality and service. Offering over 3 years of experience in industry with consistency in delivering clean, error-free, reliable code to meet current or expected needs. Well-versed in software trends and confident in multiple languages, frameworks, and programming tools.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Info Technology Analyst | NTT DATA | April 2023 – August 2023

- Executed different software projects using agile methodologies to create high-quality deliverables.
- Integrated third-party applications into existing software, enhancing features and performance.
- Participated closely with 10+ team members to identify and remove software bugs.
- Troubleshoot and debugged software to check and rectify discrepancies.
- Assisted team to complete smooth and professional software deployments using Azure Dev Ops.
- Technologies Employed: ASP .NET, SQL, Postman, Azure DevOps.

Info Technology Senior Associate | NTT DATA | August 2021 - April 2023

- Collaborated with a group of 10 tech experts, always picking up new skills and trying to have an impact on the company as a whole.
- Created 40+ Multisite Application using Sitefinity.
- Coded with .Net to build custom function for the application.
- Utilized GitHub while implementing features to push the code to staging server for testing.
- Analysed with quality assurance team with testing software, investigating bugs and developing test cases.
- Backed software code review, system integration and validation in line with company and regulatory requirements.
- Technologies Employed: ASP .NET, SQL, SITEFINITY, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub.

Web Developer | Digit Cure Growth Solutions | August 2021 - April 2023

- Sharply improved the technical skills acquired at university. Managed both front-end and back-end development for websites and web-apps using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, ReactJS, Wordpress.
- Took part in in pre-project analysis and technical assessments to validate creation of user-friendly interface.
- Revamped with designers to implement concept and design of website.
- Employed different testing tools and frameworks, content management systems and cross-functional teams to smoothly complete projects.

EDUCATION

Msc Computer Science | Queen Mary University of London | 2023 - Present

Relevant modules: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Functional Programming, Data Engineering, Security and Authentication, System Design, Risk Analysis.

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering | Goa College of Engineering | 2016 - 2020

Relevant modules: Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management System, Web Technology.

PROJECTS

Machine Learning | 2023

- Performed linear regression analysis on diabetes dataset using PyTorch, aimed on data normalization and predictive modelling.
- Implemented Mixture of Gaussians for density estimation in vowel formant frequencies, applying the EM algorithm to improve unsupervised learning accuracy by 96%.

Haskell | 2023

- Created a Haskell-based application for Population and GDP data retrieval, showcasing skills in data parsing, query processing, and resolving data inconsistencies.
- Prepared a Haskell stack application that uses threads and concurrent computation to simulate a social network.

Restaurant Management System | 2021

 Built a Restaurant Management System, crafted with Java, HTML, and CSS, seamlessly integrates with leading food delivery platforms such as Swiggy and Zomato. The system provided restaurant owners the detailed reports and visualizations, empowering strategic decision-making based on sales trends, popular menu items, and peak hours.

Deep Learning Based Attendance System | 2020

 Developed a Deep Learning Based Attendance System using the Progressive Calibration Network (PCN) for Face Detection Algorithm and One/ Few Shot Classification using Siamese Neural Networks for Face Recognition Algorithm. The process included record a short video, separating frames per minute, applying deep learning algorithm for face detection module followed by applying algorithm for face recognition.

CERTIFICATIONS

- .NET Developer, NTT DATA.
- PG Diploma in Software Development, IIIT B.

SKILLS

Python | NumPy | ASP.Net | Haskell | Java | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React JS | MySQL | Mongo | GitHub | Azure Devops | Wordpress | Shopify | Sitefinity |

Determined | Approachable | Thorough | Expressive | Energetic | Resourceful | Reliable | Quick to Adapt